[SPEAKER_01]: Where'd they go?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they're driving through Arizona and New Mexico.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's where we're going to go next.
[SPEAKER_02]: They generally go to Los Angeles, but they always stayed with me.
[SPEAKER_02]: So now they just drive through.
[SPEAKER_01]: OK. Could you tell me a little bit about your family background?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where your parents came from and what they did?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I was born in Oliphant, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I have a sister and brother living there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I have a brother in Norbert, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were your parents immigrants?
[SPEAKER_02]: Immigrants.
[SPEAKER_02]: They came from Austria-Hungary.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did your dad do?
[SPEAKER_02]: Coal miner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you work in the mines?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: I worked around the breaker until there was an attorney there, Stanley Evans.
[SPEAKER_02]: that went to Mansfield State Normal School.
[SPEAKER_02]: In this small town of Oliphant, Pennsylvania, they didn't have a high school.
[SPEAKER_02]: The highest grade was 10.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he asked me if I would go to Mansfield State Normal, he would get me a scholarship room and board.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I was the oldest in the family,
[SPEAKER_02]: and finally went to Mansfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: They played there three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this a baseball scholarship or academic?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was football, baseball, and basketball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here, I'll get it out.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was the yearbook there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's all.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was our coach.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came from your sinus.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your baseball coach at Mansfield?
[SPEAKER_02]: Football, baseball, and basketball.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, it was a state normal school.
[SPEAKER_01]: You only went through the 10th grade of high school because they didn't have any more grades?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I couldn't go to college because
[SPEAKER_02]: on account of the grades.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went to Mansfield.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the coach's name?
[SPEAKER_01]: Kickline.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kickline?
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a pretty good coach, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, where'd you play your first baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, in Oliphant.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whereabouts is Oliphant?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's about six miles north of Scranton.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stanley Kowalewski country.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came from Shamokin.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's about 60-80 miles away.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you play there at Banskia?
[SPEAKER_01]: What positions?
[SPEAKER_02]: Every place.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched, infield, I even caught.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the Knights of Columbus and all of them there, they encouraged me.
[SPEAKER_02]: What you see in those small towns,
[SPEAKER_02]: You ought to work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your picture in there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see it.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's in there three or four times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me snap your picture while you're looking there, okay?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me read this into the tape, if I may.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is his...
[SPEAKER_02]: The Caranthuan.
[SPEAKER_01]: Caranthuan, 1918.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is this your last year there?
[SPEAKER_01]: At Mansfield State.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: In Mansfield, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says Michael Gazella, Oliphant, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gazook and Mike.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Philomethean Society.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's a local society in the school there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Service society or honor society?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it's just amongst the students.
[SPEAKER_01]: Varsity football, varsity basketball, varsity baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: We point with pride to this stalwart young athlete whose touchdowns in football have made Mansfield famous and whose strikeouts in baseball are proverbial.
[SPEAKER_01]: We have found him to be a valuable asset to the school.
[SPEAKER_01]: So has Margaret.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that your wife, too?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, she's in there, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gazuk has already won a name for himself, and we expect him to take Ty Cobb's place.
[SPEAKER_01]: He dances, he sings, he plays tennis, especially love games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ask Margaret if you don't believe it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Altogether, he's a mighty fine accomplished fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the baseball team do pretty well there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You play a pretty big schedule, and who'd you play?
[SPEAKER_02]: Most of the normal schools.
[SPEAKER_01]: You graduated in 1918, then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, and then I was drafted, and I went to the Army.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was in the Army a year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was over in France.
[SPEAKER_02]: They sent me to France before I could do about face right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you see action in France?
[SPEAKER_02]: Just about.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the war end pretty soon after you got there?
[SPEAKER_01]: The armistice?
[SPEAKER_02]: After I got over there, the war ended about a month later.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, there were two armistices.
[SPEAKER_02]: One was a fake and one was the real.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you stay over in the Army of Occupation for a while?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: You came back home.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was tough to get boats to get to America.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's when I first saw Alexander Pitsch in Koblenz.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know who he was until they told me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Old Pete?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what did you do when you came back then from France?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do when you came back from France?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I came back in May or April, and I went to work for a furniture company.
[SPEAKER_02]: And from there I went to Lafayette.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was offered all kinds of scholarships from the different universities.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the reason I went to Lafayette is because it was closer to Oliphant.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lafayette is in eastern Pennsylvania, only about 60 miles away.
[SPEAKER_01]: They gave you a pretty good scholarship?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I got room and board, and after I made the varsity, I was asked to join a certain fraternity.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the reason I did it is because my three best friends that I went to Mansfield joined them.
[SPEAKER_02]: and I got room and board there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many years had you been at Mansfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: Three.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you entered Lafayette in the fall of 1919?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: As a freshman?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could have entered as a sophomore on account of my credits, but I loved sports so much that I just
[SPEAKER_02]: in it as a freshman.
[SPEAKER_01]: And did you have any plans for majors, courses?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I had no idea at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long did you go to Lafayette?
[SPEAKER_02]: Four years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, you graduated?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I graduated.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got a B.S.
[SPEAKER_02]: in chemistry.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you plan to go into business or what did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, at that time,
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't tell.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were so interested in sports.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got all kinds of offers for the big leagues in my junior year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the teams?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Brooklyn, St. Louis, New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's about all the Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't you sign?
[SPEAKER_02]: When did I sign?
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: You said this was your junior year.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I didn't sign because it was illegal.
[SPEAKER_02]: If I signed in my junior year, I couldn't play any sports in my senior year.
[SPEAKER_01]: What sports did you play, all three, at Lafayette?
[SPEAKER_02]: At Lafayette I played football and basketball, and I went out for basketball, and Jacques Sutherland, who was our coach, insisted that I stay away from basketball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said I wasn't big enough.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about football?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you play in football?
[SPEAKER_02]: halfback.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was picked on the All-America teams in juniors and seniors.
[SPEAKER_01]: EFT Is that Walter Camps All-America?
[SPEAKER_02]: MR. TABER No, not Walter Camps.
[SPEAKER_02]: Haywood Brown and Grantler Rice and Billy Evans.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I
[SPEAKER_01]: It's quite a Lafayette College Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Also, I was picked on the Lackawanna County, that's my hometown, Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's great.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can have that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Appreciate that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what did you play at Lafayette in baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Third base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I played third short and second.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, in a college team, you have to pick the man for the positions.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you didn't have a shortstop and you could play third base, you went over to short.
[SPEAKER_02]: If they didn't have a second baseman and you played the infield, they'd shift you over to second.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the way it is in those small colleges.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Sutherland the coach for all sports or just football?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your baseball coach there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Carlin.
[SPEAKER_02]: played third base for Detroit and Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Colin?
[SPEAKER_01]: Colin, C-O-U-G-H-L-I-N. Did he help you a lot or gave you some tips?
[SPEAKER_01]: He played back with the Tigers in the earlier years.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was when Cobb was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huey Jennings was running the team, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, Huey Jennings' trip to Scranton.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's only five miles from where I live.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know Huey Jennings?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember your batting average at all at Lafayette?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't keep batting averages then like they do now.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did these scouts find out about you then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, just watching the games.
[SPEAKER_02]: They went to the college gate.
[SPEAKER_02]: Back east, it's like the Pacific Coast.
[SPEAKER_02]: The scouts are all around back east.
[SPEAKER_02]: In baseball, we played Yale, Harvard, Penn University, Pennsylvania, all those big colleges.
[SPEAKER_02]: Holy Cross, Boston College, and we would beat them.
[SPEAKER_02]: At that time, they didn't pick an all-American college baseball team, but they picked the all-star baseball team, and it was on all of them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Eddie Farrell and all of those fellows up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: This picture from Holy Cross, what's his name?
[SPEAKER_02]: He went with the Giants, the time I signed with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I don't remember his name, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the Yankee scout who signed you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he was a ---- I can't remember his name now.
[SPEAKER_02]: He signed me up in the junior year, too, but I was foolish.
[SPEAKER_02]: I could have gotten more money.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was offered
[SPEAKER_02]: $5,000 from Brooklyn and $5,000 salary.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill Critchell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Paul Critchell?
[SPEAKER_02]: Paul, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you didn't go with Brooklyn and he did sign you your junior year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you weren't ineligible next year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you didn't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know this was not right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know you shouldn't have done this?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, you bet I did.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because Churchill told me, don't you ever mention this.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the way the scouts were then.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you did go and play your senior year.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I went to Mansfield, I had offers to go to
[SPEAKER_02]: Syracuse, Pittsburgh, Lehigh, all of those schools.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I met a man from over in France who was a captain of an outfit that we played against.
[SPEAKER_02]: He asked me if I'd like to go to Yale.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yale, Harvard, and Princeton in those days were like gods to us.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just shook my head.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he says, you don't have to worry.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it was really tough during those days.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, they could pull anything, not like today.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you reported to the Yankees after you graduated then in 1923?
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell me about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1923.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about that now, when you reported and what you did that first year.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did I what?
[SPEAKER_01]: What you did that first year with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seth sat on the bench.
[SPEAKER_02]: Actually, they were about five or six games ahead then, and they had men like Dugan, Scott,
[SPEAKER_02]: Ward, Pip, Musel, and Whit, and Babe Ruth, Wallace Shine-Ketchum.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't have a chance to break in.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, in those days, in those days, the managers and the coaches wanted you to imitate somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, I was a good hitter all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And because of my size, they compared me with...
[SPEAKER_02]: They wanted me to hit like this fella, hit like that fella.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was awkward.
[SPEAKER_02]: They wouldn't let me hit the way I wanted until Dugan got hit, I mean, got his finger broke, and then I won the third base.
[SPEAKER_02]: and I began to hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why didn't they farm you out or send you down for some seasoning if they couldn't play you?
[SPEAKER_02]: They bought two men from Oakland, Jimmy Reese and Lynn Larry, and they sent me out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I hit 315 in Atlanta, and I don't remember what I hit in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: What year were you at Atlanta?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Bert Niehoff was a coach there, as a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember the year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: 25.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: And in Minneapolis in 26?
[SPEAKER_01]: Twenty-four.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like Miller Huggins?
[SPEAKER_02]: All right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was sickly.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a
[SPEAKER_02]: some kind of disease that affected his legs.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't remember what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: He know how to handle players pretty well?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he had to handle them because they were winning.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't handle the Babe, I guess, but nobody could.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, if the babe only stopped drinking, he would have been playing a long time after he retired.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe and I and Gary were great friends.
[SPEAKER_02]: We played a lot of golf together in the wintertime and down in spring training.
[SPEAKER_02]: In spring training, we didn't train on Sundays.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sundays was off.
[SPEAKER_02]: But now they have exhibition games.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a whole lot different now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you meet Colonel Rupert?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was just like one of the players.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody called him Jake.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go into his office and his brewery there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever go in there?
[SPEAKER_02]: We went to the brewery after the 23 series.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a banquet there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get into the series?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play in the series in 23?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get a World Series ring then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get a World Series ring?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I couldn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had to send to Germany to have it fixed.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they didn't have parts for it anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is a watch.
[SPEAKER_01]: A five-sided watch.
[SPEAKER_01]: which on the back is inscribed, Yankees World Champions 1923.
[SPEAKER_02]: This is what we got in 1927.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 1928 we also got a wristwatch, but I gave it to my son and somebody stole it.
[SPEAKER_02]: This house was robbed.
[SPEAKER_02]: All they got was the case.
[SPEAKER_02]: The insides were stolen.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, this in 27 was a ring with the name written on the inside of the ring.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very lovely ring.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get one in 26?
[SPEAKER_02]: We lost the series then.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Escargots.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when Alex came in and struck out Lazare.
[SPEAKER_01]: Alexander.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get into that World Series?
[SPEAKER_02]: The only one I got in was, I think it was the 28th.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it was the 26th I get in because the 28th we played Pittsburgh and we beat them four straight.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you a story about that Pittsburgh World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had beaten them three straight and we came into New York.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the score was tied in the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Donnie Bush, who was manager of Pittsburgh then, changed Kramer to Mildius, Pitzer.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you imagine, the first man up doubled,
[SPEAKER_02]: Earl Combs, and Mark Koenig tried to sacrifice him over the third base, but he walked.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it put a man on first and second.
[SPEAKER_02]: And who was the next hitter?
[SPEAKER_02]: But the Bay.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he purposely walked him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there's three men on bases and nobody out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Two-two.
[SPEAKER_02]: the ninth inning, and we're playing home.
[SPEAKER_02]: So Gary comes up, and I'm a son of a gun if Mildred doesn't strike him out.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Huggins on the bench was like this.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got up.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's the only man that could walk straight up in the dugout.
[SPEAKER_01]: He kept on going back and forth.
[SPEAKER_02]: The law of averages are with us.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's impossible.
[SPEAKER_02]: A right-hand pitcher against Gehrig and doesn't even get a foul ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's not in the books.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was sitting next to Huggins, and my leg here was black and blue where he would grab for it.
[SPEAKER_02]: The next hitter up was Musial, and he looked down out there, and while the pitcher was winding up and throwing the musial, he turned and he said, what did he do?
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_02]: The crowd was, it looks like the whole stadium was for Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, strike one.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's not in the book.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just got up and down, like a law of averages and witnesses.
[SPEAKER_02]: And on the next pitch, he looked out there and wind up.
[SPEAKER_02]: And just as he threw, he turned his head, and a big roar.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_02]: He grabbed me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I says, strike two.
[SPEAKER_02]: So that went on until Lazare come up.
[SPEAKER_02]: He struck Musil out, and Lazari came up.
[SPEAKER_02]: The same thing happened on Lazari.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't seem to strike at the ball at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: And on, I think it was the 2-on-2 pitch, Milges' curveball didn't break, it must have hung.
[SPEAKER_02]: And this
[SPEAKER_02]: What was that pitcher's name?
[SPEAKER_02]: Gooch, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't reach up high enough for the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: The ball hit the tip of his glove and rolled away about 10 feet, and Earl Cohen scored, and the World Series was over.
[SPEAKER_02]: What a let-up, with all that excitement.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Huggins see that?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was tremendous, no kidding.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Huggins, was he watching that or he turned away for that pitch?
[SPEAKER_02]: I looked around for Huggins and I thought he was dead.
[SPEAKER_02]: All that excitement could have killed him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes sir, after he struck Gary out and every strike, the next two hitters,
[SPEAKER_02]: The whole stadium yelled.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did it feel like being up with the Yankees that first year in 23?
[SPEAKER_01]: You knew you were up in the big time.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't even go to the minor leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your feeling?
[SPEAKER_02]: I looked at it and I didn't feel that I was satisfied just to be on and get in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, the funniest thing about it, the players voted on what these other utility men should get.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was the time Landis become the commissioner.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he announced anyone on the ball club before July the 1st was entitled to full share.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they had me down for $500.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did you join the club?
[SPEAKER_01]: Middle of June, probably.
[SPEAKER_02]: Before July the first, in June the 24th, a week ahead of time.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the full share?
[SPEAKER_02]: How much?
[SPEAKER_02]: $6,241.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your salary that first year?
[SPEAKER_02]: $5,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was more than your salary, huh, the World Series check?
[SPEAKER_01]: World Series check was more than your salary.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do with it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I got married.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to work for an insurance company, but I didn't like the insurance company.
[SPEAKER_02]: You had to go up and try to talk them into buying insurance, and the man that
[SPEAKER_02]: I worked for.
[SPEAKER_02]: He took me down to Lafayette.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says, now try to sell some policies to the students.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, I wasn't a talker.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this in New York, the insurance company?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, in Oliphant, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was your wife from Oliphant also?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Wilkes-Barre.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got married though after the World Series in 1923?
[SPEAKER_02]: I got married about a month before the World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the Yankees send you a contract for 1924?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But did you go to spring training with them?
[SPEAKER_01]: Where was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: St. Petersburg.
[SPEAKER_01]: But then they shipped you out to Atlanta or Minneapolis?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you think about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you unhappy with that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, what could you do?
[SPEAKER_02]: What else could I do?
[SPEAKER_01]: You got a chance to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the manager up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Mike Kelly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of your teammates at Minneapolis?
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember any of those?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Pat Malone was one.
[SPEAKER_02]: Moe Berg.
[SPEAKER_02]: Huey Crites.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's pretty hard to remember them now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just imagine, this is over 50 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Minneapolis always had a pretty good team though under Mike Kelly, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's one thing I liked about Mike.
[SPEAKER_02]: He treated me pretty good.
[SPEAKER_02]: And at the season as it was over, he sent me a check.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know any better.
[SPEAKER_02]: You have so much coming.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was an honest man.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the check for?
[SPEAKER_02]: Salary.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the Yankees still owned you, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they still owed me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, then did you go with them in 25 in training?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or where did you spring train in 25?
[SPEAKER_02]: In Winter Park, Florida.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were you with then?
[SPEAKER_01]: That was Atlanta?
[SPEAKER_02]: Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bert Niehoff was the manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how did you do at Minneapolis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you hit pretty well?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember what you hit?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did they send you down to Atlanta then, a lower classification?
[SPEAKER_02]: Two ball players they bought.
[SPEAKER_02]: C-24, the Yankees were experimenting then.
[SPEAKER_02]: They got rid of Ward, Scott, Pip.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Gary made them get rid of Pip.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of a guy was Wally Pip?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of a chap was Wally Pip?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he... Every time Gary went up the... lay, he'd whisper, Plowboy Jockey.
[SPEAKER_02]: At that time, there was a lot of jealousy on them and a lot of talk until they got organized.
[SPEAKER_02]: You imagine the stars on that ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think the highest salary was
[SPEAKER_02]: about $16,000 outside of Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_02]: And today the minimum is more than $16,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was jealousy among the players over salaries?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, not over salaries, but that was a time when the college men started to get into pro football.
[SPEAKER_02]: baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you came back up in 26 then and played quite a few games.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you play?
[SPEAKER_01]: Third base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I played third short and I played a couple of games at second.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Dugan hurt?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Dugan was
[SPEAKER_02]: got his finger broken.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which position did you like the best?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, shortstop is a harder position than third base because you've got to cover more ground.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think second base is a little easier.
[SPEAKER_02]: Third base they come down, usually
[SPEAKER_02]: Those balls come really down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you ever playing third base when Ty Cobb bunted?
[SPEAKER_02]: He always dragged.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't bunt down third then?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he used to drag.
[SPEAKER_02]: He used to drag when they would knock him down.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he ever slide into third when you were playing third?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never tried to steal third?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was quite a ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he was the greatest all-around ball player, although he didn't have the personality that the Babe had on the field.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe was really a drawing card.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went into Cleveland one year, but we were on the road.
[SPEAKER_02]: And on a Sunday, they had about 10,000 people in this old county stadium that they had in Cleveland, not in this new one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lake Park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dunfield, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: And when we came in there on a Monday,
[SPEAKER_02]: They had to put ropes in the outfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: He built that stadium all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He built a lot of those other ballparks, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: He could do anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: You say you knew him pretty well.
[SPEAKER_01]: You knew him pretty well, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Are all these stories they tell about him true?
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean... What stories?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of the crazy things he does.
[SPEAKER_01]: He goes into his hotel room and buys a radio there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sees something he likes, he buys it, then leaves it when he leaves.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's rather free with his money, for example.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, at that time they didn't have radios, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the point of it was that he
[SPEAKER_01]: If he wanted something, he got it then, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd just spend money very freely and didn't worry about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Bob Musil like?
[SPEAKER_02]: Very, very quiet.
[SPEAKER_02]: Good ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was an easy going,
[SPEAKER_01]: Could really hit, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: And played that outfield and run the bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: He would only steal when you had to.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever bat against Walter Johnson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: And you knew what was coming, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get any hits off him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he strike you out?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he didn't strike me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got a piece of the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Probably the fastest pitcher ever, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was the fastest then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a chance to bat against Lefty Grove?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's pretty fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: Plenty of time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Before he become good, when he first joined the A's and he walked so many men.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ever get hit by any of these guys?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I never got hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: The only time I got hit was when Hoyt hit me in the arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: batting practice.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, Wade Hart was experimenting when he threw batting practice.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wouldn't give you a good ball of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was in and out, high and low all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a tough time getting a hold of the ball when he was up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know Bob Sharkey?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was on the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was at the 50th anniversary of the Yankees here in August.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I met Hoyt and Schalke.
[SPEAKER_01]: He pitched that first game in the new stadium in 23, when they opened Yankee Stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you hadn't joined the club yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Joe Bush?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he still in the club?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bullet Joe Bush.
[SPEAKER_02]: He liked to run around.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a very quiet fellow, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Lot of quiet people on this team, weren't there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, a girl come across the street over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look at that twist.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you look at that twist, and his wife, my wife and the other women, when it rained while we was on the road and had thunder and lightning, she would crawl under our bed.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tony had epilepsy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get a seizure out in the field you know of?
[SPEAKER_02]: There's one thing about Tony, he rooms with Mark Cornick and Huggins told Mark Cornick whenever Tony shaved to be in the same room with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he must have had an elliptic attack when he fell down those stairs at his home out in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's just before he died, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it like when Alexander pitched against him in the 26th World Series?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're on the bench there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They bring Alex in.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was pretty exciting, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not any different than any other pitcher, but you wanted to see what he had.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had that screwball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a slider, too, at that time, and a good curveball.
[SPEAKER_02]: He wasn't exceedingly fast, but he knew where he was going to throw it.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, he had good control.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he had a big night the night before.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tough assignment for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it the last game when Ruth tried to steal second and was thrown out stealing?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ruth had, I guess he was a tying runner or something on first base, but threw out and tried to steal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bob O'Farrell was the cardinal captain.
[SPEAKER_01]: I talked to him once up in, he's up in Waukegan, Illinois, and he described that.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was told not to steal bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: Could steal bases all right, but Huggins didn't want him to.
[SPEAKER_02]: Man like that can't afford to lose him with a broken leg or a sprained ankle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Luke Gehrig was another quiet one, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He spoke with his bat.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a little more hustle than, well, the reason was that Babe was in the outfield and you couldn't tell and Garrick was in the infield and he would hustle around there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a kind of a leader?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who?
[SPEAKER_01]: Garrick?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the
[SPEAKER_01]: a leader in that infield, somebody, a take-charge guy, anybody like that, like Blaseri, maybe?
[SPEAKER_01]: Somebody who exerted leadership in the infield?
[SPEAKER_02]: Not anybody in particular.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mark Koenig wasn't that type?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Koenig, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a careless guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Careless?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he still living, do you know?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he lives up in Boyce Springs.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's across the Golden Gate Bridge there.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're going up that way, I'm going to try to see him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't go to the 50th anniversary, I don't know why.
[SPEAKER_02]: They pulled a dirty deal on him and the Cubs when he went out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: In fact, he won the pennant for them and they only voted him a quarter of a share in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was lousy.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when Ruth pointed at them.
[SPEAKER_01]: They thought he was pointing at them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember Ruth's 60th home run at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I really do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you tell me about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: There isn't anything to tell.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a big excitement when he hit that one?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, just... You didn't have the crowds then like you have now.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they all went over and
[SPEAKER_02]: congratulated him, both teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: I believe today he would hit a 100 home runs with this ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or he'd get over 100 walks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they walk him much?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Gary coming up?
[SPEAKER_02]: When the score was tied, he'd come up to hit.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd walk him.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Gary?
[SPEAKER_02]: Almost the same with Gary, although they were told to be more careful and make him hit a bad ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Wally Shang still with them when you – in the later years?
Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pretty good catcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Good fellow, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of pep.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a take-charge guy, maybe, in that team.
[SPEAKER_02]: I remember a time in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was the Holloman Hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had a little fountain in the lobby.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was some fish in it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of the boys were sitting on the cement there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you want a fish?
[SPEAKER_02]: He pushed him in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was up there one day in the room watching them play.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was it poker or pinochle?
[SPEAKER_02]: And Wally was in the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they come over.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, this is a good shirt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you like it?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He tore it.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, they used to tear pajamas in the sleepers, go around up berths.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nobody slept in an upper.
[SPEAKER_02]: The baggage went up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody had a lower.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had some long train rides, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Still, I'll say.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it hot in the summer?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you ever sleep in some of those hot Pullmans, I wonder?
[SPEAKER_01]: No air conditioning?
[SPEAKER_01]: Must have been pretty hard to sleep.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just had to sleep, that's all.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe had a compartment.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was the babe, so...
[SPEAKER_01]: He got special treatment.
[SPEAKER_02]: The same way he had a suite of rooms.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he had to.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had so much company.
[SPEAKER_02]: Newspaper among everybody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wanted to see the babe.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he had most of his meals in his room.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you like the umpires?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, they're not any different than now, although they are more than now.
[SPEAKER_02]: They only had three then.
[SPEAKER_01]: They do a pretty good job, would you say?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they're not any better than they are now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now they train the umpires.
[SPEAKER_01]: You never got thrown out of a game.
[SPEAKER_02]: In Minneapolis I got thrown out.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_02]: Argue with the umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought I had the play beat out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went like that and he thought I was raising my fist to hit him.
[SPEAKER_02]: My size we were going to challenge.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember Bill Guthrie?
[SPEAKER_02]: If you write anything about it, don't say anything about this.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you a story about Bill Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe Ruth was up there hitting, and somebody told Bill Guthrie, one of the umpires, that you couldn't call Babe out on the third strike.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you know, Guthrie had an old neck, a bullneck old.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he always says, these, those, and them.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he says, well, if I put up all the rovers, I'll call the strike.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he did call Babe out on the third strike.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Babe was arguing there, arguing with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And finally, it got to the Huggins.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came out with, you know, only one about this high on Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he started arguing with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he says, you order the ball game and take the bat boy with you.
[SPEAKER_02]: He told me, you order the ball game and take the bat boy with you.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Huggins told him then, you're finished.
[SPEAKER_01]: Told who?
[SPEAKER_02]: Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the following year he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know you can't insult a guy like Huggins on a championship ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Bill Dineen around then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: An old pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: McGowan, I guess, was a pretty good umpire.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a lively guy, Bill McGowan.
[SPEAKER_02]: Clarence Rowland was the... forget about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: If you missed the first pitch, he called him a striker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did a bottle.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's only one strike.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was a...
[SPEAKER_01]: Pants are off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any pick-off plays worked out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they pick a guy off first or third?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you recall?
[SPEAKER_02]: Very seldom did they pick him off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Catch your throat a third or something like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what was it like?
[SPEAKER_01]: You were on the greatest team ever there in 27, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: There'd been some great teams, but that probably... Well, it's pretty hard to pick the great teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: Look at the Cincinnati ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't have any pitching, though, but the Yankees had great pitching and great hitting and great defense.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had you been on some other team, do you think you would have been playing regular?
[SPEAKER_01]: If you were on some other team besides the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Peckinpah wanted to buy me when he was managing Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_02]: You see, some of those regulars weren't getting as much money as I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, in Cleveland they had a, what do they call it, a city ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I doubt if you could get 25,000 people in it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they weren't drawing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you mean some of the Cleveland players weren't getting as much as you were on the Yankees?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, a lot of them were in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, why didn't he get you if he wanted you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Peckinpah wanted you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Peckinpah, he tried to get you, but he couldn't?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wouldn't the Yankees sell you or trade you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, maybe, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe I was on waivers and they claimed me and the Yankees dropped it.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the only way I could figure it.
[SPEAKER_02]: At that St. Louis ball club, when Phil Ball was the owner, there weren't very many.
[SPEAKER_02]: Washington, another ball club, wasn't paying much.
[SPEAKER_02]: Washington, St. Louis, Cleveland,
[SPEAKER_01]: Chicago probably.
[SPEAKER_01]: Comiskey never paid very much money there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Detroit paid good.
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened after the 28th season?
[SPEAKER_01]: The winter of 28, I worked
[SPEAKER_02]: down on Wall Street.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 29, the Yankees wanted to send me to Jersey City.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I wanted $6,000, and they would only give me $5,500.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I put on a voluntary retired list.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then the market broke, remember, in 29?
[SPEAKER_02]: And the Yankees sold me to Hollywood.
[SPEAKER_02]: I played in the Coast League.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we won the pennant three straight years there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play with Hollywood in 29, or did you sit out 29?
[SPEAKER_01]: I sat out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a job?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that when you were with Wall Street?
[SPEAKER_01]: And so you went to Hollywood in 29?
[SPEAKER_02]: I went to Hollywood in 30.
[SPEAKER_02]: Played there 30, 31, 32, 30, 31, 32.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I went over to Los Angeles in 33 and 34.
[SPEAKER_02]: And finally they asked me if I wanted to manage one of their
[SPEAKER_02]: in my league teams.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went to Ponca City and managed that team for the Los Angeles Ball Club and won the pennant two straight years there.
[SPEAKER_01]: What years were those, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that was...
[SPEAKER_02]: 30, 31, 32, 33, 35, and 36.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 37 and 38, I went to Moline and one dependent there for two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you playing?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: You finished after the years in
[SPEAKER_01]: L.A., was that your last plane?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, uh, then in what years I went up to manage Denver.
[SPEAKER_02]: Forty-five and forty-six.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anyhow, I went working for Lockheed, and I
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm drawing a pension from Lockheed.
[SPEAKER_02]: After Denver, I finally decided to quit and stay home.
[SPEAKER_02]: Sick and tired of traveling and work there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where was your home then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Los Angeles.
[SPEAKER_01]: You made that your permanent home then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I bought a house there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lived in it for 25 years, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like playing ball on the Coast Lake?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, good.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wonderful weather.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had a long season, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: They played real long seasons.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was a month longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was DiMaggio playing with the Seals when you were out there?
[SPEAKER_02]: He joined the Seals when I was on the Hollywood Ball Club, 1930, 31.
[SPEAKER_02]: Either 31 or 32, he joined them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Big lanky kid.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he hit a whole lot different than he does now when he did with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: He spread out with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_02]: When he was at the Coast League, he stood straight up.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a lot of ballplayers who went to big leagues from that Coast League.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a nice league.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dandy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Six or seven game series, wouldn't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: A week, yeah, a whole week.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cut down on travel, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mondays was off.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd go up to Frisco and you'd play, uh, Seals, seven games, and Missions, and... Boulder, Oakland, and play there.
[SPEAKER_01]: You stay in the same hotel and you're playing all around the...
[SPEAKER_02]: Then when you went up north, you played Sacramento, Portland, and Seattle.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, that Sacramento was a hot town.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Sandy?
[SPEAKER_02]: On Sundays, you'd go over to, oh, they'd play in a small town over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I took deuces in that town.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because Sacramento didn't draw so good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Jolly out in the Coast Lake Speed?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Buzz Arlett?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That guy was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he's always drunk, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he hit right and left hand.
[SPEAKER_02]: Right and left hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Paul Strand was not there, was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was earlier, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who managed the Hollywood team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oscar Witt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Oscar Witt.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he went up to Newark.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the LA?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the Angels?
[SPEAKER_01]: Los Angeles?
[SPEAKER_02]: It was Jack Lillibelt.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a beautiful ballpark, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wrigley Field?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, both teams played in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hollywood and the... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a Vernon team then?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that was before then.
[SPEAKER_02]: when they played on Washington Street there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then when Wrigley Field was built, Vernon was sold for business property and they came over there and played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, it's a funny thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: At the Vernon Ballpark, they had a big water tank in Center Field.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's where they got their hot water from.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right in the playing field?
[SPEAKER_02]: To take their showers.
[SPEAKER_02]: They didn't have furnaces or anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: They would use the water out of the tank for their showers.
[SPEAKER_01]: How were the locker room facilities out there?
[SPEAKER_01]: They were pretty good?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: for the most part?
[SPEAKER_02]: They were all pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't have to change in the hotel and come out to the ballpark?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what was the biggest thrill you had in baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything stand out?
[SPEAKER_02]: Watching Babe Ruth hit most of the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wade Hoyt pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Also, Herb Pennock pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Watching those good Johnson pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: But to yourself, did you have any big days, either the majors or the minors, that stand out?
[SPEAKER_01]: You could ever go six for six in three home runs in a game or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing stands out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Nothing stands out in your own mind, you know, big day?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the funniest thing you ever saw in a ballpark during a game?
[SPEAKER_02]: The funniest?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: anything funny.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, it's a strenuous game, playing every day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Today, at my age, I wonder how we did it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have lights out on the Pacific Coast for night baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: Later on they did, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some of those lights were brutal.
[SPEAKER_02]: In Los Angeles, when they put them in, they had a light behind home plate there, and if the ball hit a ground ball, you had a deuce of a time seeing it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got here one day,
[SPEAKER_02]: right on the lip.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Homosuma was the one that hit it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was in for a month.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some of the parks, the lights, if you hit in the lights in a certain area, you got a home run.
[SPEAKER_02]: But if it hit the lights, I mean if it hit the lights and came back, and if it hit below the wall, you only get two bases.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in Sacramento, on 3rd base, if you hit a high fly, boy, you're in a hell of a time trying to catch it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we had difficulty with the lights.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're not quite as bright as they are now, are they?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you like the night?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you like the idea of playing at night?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not out in the Coast League.
[SPEAKER_02]: In Los Angeles it was terrible.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had to wear woolen socks because it was damp.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Ponca City?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have lights?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, Ponca City had lights.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hell, in Oklahoma, it's hot all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: The bugs would fly amongst the light and they'd burst them.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about riding the buses?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ride many buses?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, in Park City and Moline.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have to drive?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, it was terrible.
[SPEAKER_02]: buses.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ride all night to get to one place or another.
[SPEAKER_01]: To sleep on the bus, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Where to sleep all day?
[SPEAKER_02]: You could sleep on the bus all night.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a laugh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ponca City was dry and what was that
[SPEAKER_02]: not Springfield, but this town next to Springfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anyhow, we were told to sneak over some liquor from Springfield to Ponca City.
[SPEAKER_02]: One day, we were driving to
[SPEAKER_02]: from Ponca City to Bartlesville, and the God darn, that door opened and we lost all the suits they had to go back for.
[SPEAKER_02]: What is that town?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Oklahoma or Missouri?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, it's in
[SPEAKER_02]: Springfield, Missouri.
[SPEAKER_02]: This side of Springfield, it's only about 40 miles.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a lead country, copper company.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was the Western Association?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joplin's the other way.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joplin it is.
[SPEAKER_02]: Out of Joplin.
[SPEAKER_02]: Try to sneak in liquor.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you like managing?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was all right outside riding the buses.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any discipline problems with some of those players?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, not much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any of the boys you managed make it to the big league?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: This Majewski.
[SPEAKER_02]: and Rip Russell, Higby, and the first baseman that went to the Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Young?
[SPEAKER_01]: Babe Young?
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the meal money out there in the West Coast?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do they give you enough money to eat off of?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you ought to be careful.
[SPEAKER_02]: You wouldn't get a hell of a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: Although things were cheap then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jesus, I don't know how long this is going to last, this inflation.
[SPEAKER_02]: Boy, it's terrible.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do in the off-season?
[SPEAKER_01]: Between you?
[SPEAKER_02]: When I lived in Los Angeles, I worked for Lockheed.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do there?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was a jig builder.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you just really stayed on with them then after you quit baseball, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any other stories you can think of or anecdotes or remembrances?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a great life.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, I'm 82 years old and
[SPEAKER_02]: There's too many of these stories.
[SPEAKER_02]: My memory is not so good anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some very good stories there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there's loads of stories.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just to have known the babe and some of those other people.
[SPEAKER_01]: Must have been a great life.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we'll shut this off now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is the next night after the interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: The interview was on Tuesday night, June 6th in Odessa, Texas with Mike Gazzella.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is now Wednesday night, June 7th, and we're at the
[SPEAKER_00]: in our tent site here, a rocky glass, broken glass, strewn cactus, surrounded, unshaded site here in White City, New Mexico, which is about seven miles north of the Carlsbad Caverns, which we did visit this afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: We drove from Odessa this morning to Picos, where we had a real nice visit in Picos.
[SPEAKER_00]: with the museum there of the old Orient Hotel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had some music by the player piano.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then on to the Roy Bean reconstructed law office, a replica of it, the real one's down in Plantry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we drove on up here, got in about 2 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: But because of the change in time as we crossed the New Mexico border, at around 20 of
[SPEAKER_00]: 1, it became 20 of 12.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so we picked up an hour.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now it's 8 o'clock tonight, and it's really 9 o'clock by last night's time and 10 o'clock by Williamstown time in the eastern zone.
[SPEAKER_00]: This interview last night was a very difficult one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had not written to Gazella.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, we had expected to go up to Lubbock
[SPEAKER_00]: and interview Sam West, but from all we heard about Sam West because of his mother's illness, we heard at the knots when we visited them and we heard it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I heard on the phone, I talked to Mrs. West on Sunday, that it's unlikely we would have been able to get an interview or that he wanted to talk much in Lubbock if we had gotten up there under these circumstances.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we decided to not go to Lubbock and go to Odessa and take a chance on visiting with Mike Gazella.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we arrived in Odessa yesterday afternoon from
[SPEAKER_00]: Brown, Lake Brownwood.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got his address and went out to his house.
[SPEAKER_00]: Called him first, but he didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody answered.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then we drove out to his house, which is on Hanley Street on one of the outskirts of Odessa, which is a pretty nice town, an oil town.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of money, beautiful university.
[SPEAKER_00]: or a college, Odessa College, about 10,000 seat stadium, and a reconstructed Globe Theater of the perfect model of theater in England.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was Shakespeare's Theater.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got into that briefly last night.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we went out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after I called him and got no answer, we just thought we'd drive out and see him and get a place to stay.
[SPEAKER_00]: We found the place all right on Hanley.
[SPEAKER_00]: parked there, and there was a wizened old man reading the paper on the porch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it looked like he might be Mike Pazella.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I went over there, and the dog started barking.
[SPEAKER_00]: Two huge dogs barked to beat the band.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't hear myself think.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't hear anyhow.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was very deaf.
[SPEAKER_00]: So trying to explain what I was talking about, what I was there for, coming just off the street to a man who was deaf and with a couple of barking dogs,
[SPEAKER_00]: an experience you'll have to go through to really appreciate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Finally, he got the dogs shut up in a back room and came out and invited me into the living room.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I explained then better what I was all about.
[SPEAKER_00]: He finally was able to listen and hear better.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got my point across and I asked him if I could see him at, say, 7 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was then about 4.
[SPEAKER_00]: in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, yeah, he could see me and get some stuff out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's staying with his son there.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife had died some years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he sold his home in Los Angeles and moved to Odessa, where his son is an executive with a local television station.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they have a couple of kids and a couple of dogs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they're all on vacation, left him with the dogs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, they're spoiled, those dogs are.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, they were yelling all over the place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we went in and got a hotel room at the Travel Lodge in Odessa and then had a bite to eat at what they call a steak and eggs place nearby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then we drove out and visited the, saw the Globe Theater, saw the world's largest jackrabbit, a little 12-foot statue there in downtown Odessa, took a picture of that, and saw a few of the sights.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very wide streets and a rather nice city.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I guess we'd done that first after we got cleaned up and I got my notes ready for the interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the motel then, we did the sightseeing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then went to Steak and Eggs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I dropped Rita off and I drove out to Gisela's house and got there about 7 o'clock just on time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought it would be a good interview because he had a loud voice and he seemed to be ready to talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as it turned out, he didn't say much.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there are many gaps, as you can hear, on the tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: would say something, and I thought he was going to follow up and elaborate and say more.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he just shut up then, and I had to start something new.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it seemed like I was always starting something new.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to break in with some, after almost an indecent pause, I'd have to start up on another subject.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was difficult to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had some pretty good stories, but they were
[SPEAKER_00]: I almost felt like I was wrenching them out of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Occasionally, I'd mention something, and he'd light up and lean forward and tell a story.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mentioned Bill Guthrie, and he told the story about Miller, Huggins, and Ruth, and he told Guthrie through Ruth, out of the game, I'd take your bat boy with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, Huggins got Guthrie for that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he wasn't in the league the next year, although I don't know he ever could do anything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a little house, one story, I guess, and not too many rooms.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rather neat inside.
[SPEAKER_00]: We sat in the living room, and the door was open.
[SPEAKER_00]: A wind began to blow about halfway through there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought, you know, blow the whole thing down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Terrific ale.
[SPEAKER_00]: We heard later on there were terrific storms all over Texas, mostly north and east of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Flood warnings out in the valley, and tornadoes in various places.
[SPEAKER_00]: just apparently high winds, though, in the Odessa-Midland area, although they said the streets in Big Spring or Odessa, or not Odessa, but Pecos were covered with water, so it was all around us, apparently, the wind and the rain.
[SPEAKER_00]: But actually, it seemed quite nice in the motel room the last time we all had—we both had the best sleeps we've had, probably, in this trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all he brought out is your book for
[SPEAKER_00]: Mansfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mansfield must have been kind of a normal school, a high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went there three years to finish up his high school, then went to Lafayette.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he didn't have a yearbook for Lafayette.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the one for Mansfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: He brought out a couple of folders full of pictures and clippings.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't really get a chance to look at the clippings or the mementos very much.
[SPEAKER_00]: A couple of
[SPEAKER_00]: of banquets where he was honored.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the program with the speakers and the menu and so on in the printed, folded menu there.
[SPEAKER_00]: One from Lafayette, one old-timers, a banquet he attended and was honored at.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pictures were not much.
[SPEAKER_00]: A couple of Hollywood stars.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I took copies, made copies with my 35-millimeter camera of most of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I haven't known if they'll come out or not, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had enough light and the light meter looked like it was registering all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Otherwise, holding the camera steady is another matter.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'll have to see how those pictures came out.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of the dogs came in during the interview, or I guess when we were about through and I was looking at pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was actually very quiet then.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was friendly and didn't make a bit of noise.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just nestled down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: and watch proceedings from his vantage point on the floor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took me out into his bedroom, went to the dining room, and then into his bedroom off the dining room, which he had some pictures on the wall there, a couple of little trophies.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he just didn't say much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had just so much he could have said.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it seemed like a time he just
[SPEAKER_00]: didn't want to remember, or maybe he didn't think I'd be interested in his remembering.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just didn't elaborate the way I thought he would, because he was a bright enough chap, although he did have a stroke, as you mentioned, and probably that hurt, bothered his memory a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when he got going, though, he expressed himself well enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was not an easy interview.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was constantly having to prime him for
[SPEAKER_00]: more information and sometimes it couldn't respond much to my prayer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stories about Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: What stories?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh my God, there are all kinds of stories about Ruth and drinking and women and his carrying on and his spending of money and doing this.